Guide to the Cable 13 Videotapes, 1976 - 1982
University Archives Duke University
Cable 13 Videotapes 1976 - 1982
Cable 13 (Television station: Durham, N.C.)
18 Linear Feet, 250 Items
University Archives, Duke University
Duke Union Community Television (Cable 13), Duke's student-run television station, grew out of Freewater Films' video programming group, following the purchase of a television camera. Cable 13 was the first student-owned and student-run television station in the country. Cable 13 became an official committee of the Duke University Union in 1976. It broadcasts on the Duke campus cable system. The collection consists of approximately 250 U-Matic videocassettes and half-inch open reel videotapes of events recorded at and around Duke between 1976 and 1982. Interviews include William S. Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, Nikki Giovanni, Juanita Kreps, Joseph Kruzel, Henry Kyemba, Peter Orlovsky, Terry Sanford, and Daniel Schorr. Performances include Dance Black, the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, the Firesign Theatre, Jerry Garcia, Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus, and Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd. Events include basketball, women's crew, football, soccer, volleyball, women's volleyball, and Joe College Weekend.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Use of this collection requires the creation of viewing copies from videotapes. However, University Archives does not have the equipment or the resources to make copies from U-Matic videocassettes or half-inch open reel video. To arrange for the creation of use copies from these formats, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The majority of the tapes in the Cable 13 Videotapes collection were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1981, accession number UA81-42. Some tapes were added to the collection after that date.
Historical Note
Duke Union Community Television (Cable 13), Duke's student-run television station, grew out of Freewater Films' video programming group, following the purchase of a television camera. Cable 13 was the first student-owned and student-run television station in the country. Cable 13 became an official committee of the Duke University Union in 1976. It broadcasts on the Duke campus cable system.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of approximately 250 U-Matic videocassettes and half-inch open reel videotapes of events recorded at and around Duke between 1976 and 1982. Interviews include William S. Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, Nikki Giovanni, Juanita Kreps, Joseph Kruzel, Henry Kyemba, Peter Orlovsky, Terry Sanford, and Daniel Schorr. Performances include Dance Black, the Duke Symphony Orchestra, the Duke Wind Symphony, the Firesign Theatre, Jerry Garcia, Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus, and Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd. Events include basketball, women's crew, football, soccer, volleyball, women's volleyball, and Joe College Weekend.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Burroughs, William S., 1914-
Cable 13 (Television station: Durham, N.C.)
Duke University -- Basketball
Duke University -- Crew -- Women's
Duke University. Dance Black
Duke University -- Football
Duke University -- Joe College Weekend
Duke University -- Soccer
Duke University. Symphony Orchestra
Duke University -- Volleyball
Duke University -- Volleyball -- Women's.
Duke University Wind Symphony
Firesign Theatre (Performing group)
Garcia, Jerry, 1942-
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-
Giovanni, Nikki
Kreps, Juanita Morris
Kyemba, Henry, 1939-
Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus
McGuinn, Roger
Sanford, Terry, 1917-
Schorr, Daniel, 1916-
Videotapes
Contents of Collection
- Accession A81-42
  Each show or project was give a volume number when it was recorded. The volume number can refer to a single tape, or it can refer to multiple tapes that make up a show or project. That numbering system has been maintained, and tapes are stored in numerical order by volume number. To facilitate research and the location of tapes, all tapes are presented in this finding aid in alphabetical order by title with their corresponding box and volume numbers.
  - American Ballet. Page Auditorium, 1978 Feb. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 10, Vol. 116)
  - Anderson, Jack. Page Auditorium, 1976 Nov. 17, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 20)
  - Another Saturday Night, undated., 3 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 97)
  - Anything Goes, 1977 Apr. 20, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 96)
  - Anything Goes: Student Locator, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 18)
  - Anything Goes: Student Locator, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 84)
  - Arnold, Jim. Party, 1976 Nov. 19, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 25 min. (Box 10, Vol. 133)
  - ASDU Candidates, 1977 Nov. 2, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 76)
  - ASDU Presidential Forum, 1977 Nov. 9, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 75)
  - ASDU Presidential Forum, 1978 Nov. 8, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 77)
  - ASDU Symposium: Presidents, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 1, Vol. 5)
  - As-Salaam Alaikum: Do You Thank Allah for Another Day, 1976 Nov. 29, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 10, Vol. 117)
  - Atlanta Ballet, 1978 Apr. 11, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 103)
  - Barkin, Alan. Party, 1976 Oct. 31, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 11 min. (Box 10, Vol. 115)
  - Basketball: Banks, Dennard, Scrimmage, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 118)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. North Carolina State University, 1977 Jan. 22, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Vol. 36)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. St. Josephs, 1977 Apr. 5, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Vol. 38)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. UVA, 1977 Feb. 9, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 86)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. Wake Forest University, 1977 Feb. 2, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 4, Vol. 39)
  - Basketball: Duke vs. Washington College, 1977 Nov. 29, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Vol. 40)
  - Best Years of our Lives, 1977 Feb. 21, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Vol. 60)
  - Bird, Tony, 1976 Nov. 23, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 9, Vol. 105)
  - Campbell, Will, 1977 Jan. 31, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 6, Vol. 71)
  - Celebration of Spring, 1976, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 119)
  - Celebration of Spring, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Vol. 31)
  - Celebration of Spring: Highlights, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Vol. 28)
  - Celebration of Spring: Roving camera, crafts, 1976 Apr. 23, 3 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 3, Vol. 29)
  - Celebration of Spring: Various Groups, 1976 Apr. 23, 7 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 3, Vol. 30)
  - Citizen Flash, 1976, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 94)
  - Cousins, Norman: Speech, Closing, UNC Survival Symposium, 1976 Apr. 2, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 16)
  - Dance Black, 1980 Feb. 27, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 111)
  - Dance Black Concert: Pamoja Sisi Kucheza, 1976 Mar. 18, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 6)
  - Dance Black: Essence of Black. Page Auditorium, 1976 Feb. 17, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 120)
  - Doc on Docs: Anne Hodges, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 122)
  - Documentary Idea, 1977, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 87)
  - Duke Campaign '77: Candidate Advertising spots, 1977 Feb. 19, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Vol. 26)
  - Duke Campaign '77: ASDU Election Forum, 1977 Feb. 2, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 74)
  - Duke Dance, 1976 Nov. 16, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 13)
  - Duke Dance: Leap Year Dance Show, 1976 Feb. 29, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 14)
  - Duke Symphony, 1977 Oct. 14, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Vol. 58)
  - Duke Symphony, 1978 Dec., 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 92)
  - Duke Symphony Orchestra, 1977 Mar. 2, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 7)
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1977 Mar. 26, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 8)
  - Duke Wind Symphony, 1977 Nov. 19, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 9)
  - Durden, Robert, 1978 Mar. 10, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 10, Vol. 123)
  - Durham Street Fair and Toilet Tape, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 10, Vol. 124)
  - Election '76: Joel Smith interview, 1976 Nov. 2, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 125)
  - Election '76: Terry Sanford interview, undated, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 126)
  - Energy You Save May be your Own, 1977 Dec. 16, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 65)
  - Fashion comes to Duke: Nina Hyde interview, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 127)
  - Firesign Theatre, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 5, Vol. 59)
  - Football: Duke vs. Clemson, 1976 Oct. 16., 3 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 4, Vol. 35)
  - Football: Duke vs. NCSU, 1976, 3 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 4, Vol. 33)
  - Football: Duke vs. NCSU post-game show, 1976, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 4, Vol. 34)
  - Football: Duke vs. USC, 1976, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 4, Vol. 32)
  - Future of Public Broadcasting Seminar, 1979 Jan. 21, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 129)
  - Galloping Guzzler, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 83)
  - Garcia, Jerry: Concert at Duke University, 1976 Apr. 5, 3 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch (marked "EIAJ standard"). (Box 2, Vol. 23)
  - Giovanni, Nikki, 1977 Nov. 10, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 95)
  - Gutman, Herbert. Panel Discussion, 1976 Nov. 8, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 15)
  - H-Bomb Concert [Peter Holsapple and the H-Bombs], 1977 Mar. 18, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 100)
    - Reference Copy: DVD. UA81-42-2.
  - Herpes, 1977 Nov., 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 88)
  - Hillside Commercials, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 10 min. (Box 10, Vol. 130)
  - Hingston, Sandy: A Song in the Garden, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 63)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1977 Mar. 22, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 6, Vol. 70)
  - Homecoming. Wallace Wade Stadium, 1976, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 131)
  - Housing Shortage at Duke, 1977 Oct. 26, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 93)
  - Hungry for Change: Thoughts from a College Campus, 1982 June, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 112)
  - Joe College: Springfest '77--bands, interviews, beer-chugging contest, 1977 Apr. 15, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 60 min. (Box 10, Vol. 134)
  - Joe College: Saturday--Scenes, 1977 Apr. 16, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 15 min. (Box 11, Vol. 135)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Interviews with Mark and Seth, 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 136)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Preservation Jazz Co., 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 137)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd, 1977 Apr. 17, 3 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 80 min. (Box 11, Vol. 138)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Southwing and Preservation Jazz. Co., 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 139)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Southwing, 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 140)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Tall Dogs, 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 141)
  - Joe College: Sunday--Tall Dogs, Roger McGuinn and Thunderbyrd, 1977 Apr. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 30 min. (Box 11, Vol. 142)
  - Kennedy Interview, undated, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. none)
  - Klesch, Gary, 1976 Nov. 3, 3 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 19)
  - Kolisch and Kertzner Interviews, 1977 Sept. 29, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 3, Vol. 27)
  - Kolisch, John: Performance, 1977 Sept. 28, 3 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 57)
  - Kreps, Juanita, and Amanda Smith, undated, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 10)
  - Kruzel, Joseph: Ford and Carter Foreign Policy, 1976 Oct. 5, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 17)
  - Kyemba, Henry: Interview, 1978 Feb. 14, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 67)
  - Kyemba, Henry: Speech, question and answer session, 1978 Feb. 14, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 66)
  - LITE Summer Games, 1982 June 26-27, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 114)
  - Lotte Goslar's Pantomime Circus, 1977 Apr. 6, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 143)
  - Lovejoy: Nuclear Energy Debate, undated, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 99)
  - Mann, Glenn E. (Ted): Interview, 1982 July 5, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 113)
  - Mathias, Charles, Senator: Panel Interview, 1977 Nov. 18, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 101)
  - McAlister, Elizabeth, 1976 Apr. 2, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 3, Vol. 25)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1976 Sept. 29, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch (reel #1 of 3 missing). (Box 5, Vol. 46)
  - New Performing Dance Co., 1976 Nov. 30, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 11)
  - Paletz, David: Media in the Campaign, undated, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 3, Vol. 24)
  - Phelps, Jake: Director, University Union, 1978 Apr. 5, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 146)
  - Pig Roast: Woods Scene, 1977 Nov. 14, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. 15 min. (Box 11, Vol. 147)
  - Pig Roast: Caldwell Community College, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 148)
  - Pig Roast: Lost Tape #1, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 149)
  - Pig Roast: Early Morning Sunrise, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. none)
  - Pig Roast: Ride in Truck, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. none)
  - Pigskin Profile, 1978 Oct. 8, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 9, Vol. 102)
  - Polo, M. W., undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 144)
  - Primate Center, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 91)
  - Psychic Research: Mysteries of the Mind, 1977 Nov. 11, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 81)
  - Pure Prairie League: Cameron Hall, 1977 Mar. 18, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 41)
  - Reid, Robin: Interview by Chapel and interview with Larry in Jones Bldg, 1977 Dec. 5, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 10, Vol. 132)
  - Salamon, Lester: Domestic issues in the campaign, 1976 Oct. 19, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 22)
  - Sanford, Terry: A talk with Terry Sanford, 1977 Oct. 17, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 64)
    - Reference Copy: VHS. UA81-42-1.
  - Schorr, Daniel: Major Speaker's address on the West Union Quad, 1976 Apr. 21, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 7, Vol. 73)
  - Schorr, Daniel: Panel Discussion, 1976 Apr. 21, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. 45 min. (Box 6, Vol. 72)
  - Sidey, Hugh, undated, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 2, Vol. 21)
  - Soccer II, 1976 Nov. 19, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. 60 min. (Box 11, Vol. 150)
  - Soccer: Duke vs. UNC-Wilmington, 1976 Oct. 19, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 42)
  - Solitaire: Original Music by Dave Feinman and Bill Needell, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 62)
  - Storaska, Frederic, 1978 Sept. 15, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 78)
  - Strategies for Human and Technological Progress: Global Ecological Agriculture, 1977 Mar. 16, 4 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 9, Vol. 104)
  - Toad the Mime, undated 1977 Feb. 13, 2 videocassettes (U-matic). (Box 6, Vol. 61)
  - Together After 20 Years, Part 1: Allen Ginsberg, William Burroughs, and Peter Orlorsky at the UNC Chapel Hill Fine Arts Festival, 1977 Mar. 17, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 98)
  - Town and Gown, 1977 Dec. 7, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 8, Vol. 93)
  - Turner, Mrs., undated, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 11, Vol. 151)
  - UNC-Chapel Hill Lab Band and The Duke Jazz Ensemble, 1977 Feb. 8, 2 video reels; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 1, Vol. 3)
  - Volleyball: Duke vs. NCSU, undated, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 43)
  - Volleyball: Women's Varsity UNCCH 1976 Oct. 26, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. 152)
  - Ways of Life, 1977 Mar. 17, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 6, Vol. 69)
  - Wittles, Martha: Making the invisible visible, 1977 Apr. 12, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 82)
  - Woman's Crew, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic). (Box 7, Vol. 79)
  - Woman's Crew, 1977 Nov. 28 and 1977 Dec. 6, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 9, Vol. 106)
  - Woman's Crew, 1977 Dec. 6, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. 153)
  - Women's Tennis: Duke vs. UVA, 1976, 1 video reel; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 45)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. UNC-Ch, North Carolina State Volleyball Tournament, 1976 Nov., 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 44)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. ECU, 1977 Oct. 11, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. 154)
  - Women's Volleyball, 1976 Oct. 19, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 5, Vol. 47)
  - Women's Volleyball: Duke vs. UNC-Ch, 1976 Oct. 11, 1 video reel; 7-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. 155)
  - Yale Alleycats: Cambridge Inn. 1978 Mar. 22, 2 video reels; 5-inch, 1/2 inch. (Box 12, Vol. 156)